牢记
Remember...
我刚满65岁
I just turned 65.
我在生日那天许下一个愿望
I made a wish on my birthday.
像孩子一样
Just like a child would...
当然，那是一个不可能实现的愿望
Another impossible wish, of course.
你知道我许了什么愿吗？
You know what I wished for?
我想做好人
To be a good man.
你了解我
You know me.
是的
I do.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
杀
KILL
内斯林，用枪指着人和开枪是两码事
Nesrin, pulling a gun is so different than to pulling the trigger.
你不能在互联网或电视上找到任何这样的素材
You couldn't find any of this footage on the internet or on TV.
欢迎来到首个真正的土耳其连环杀手的粉丝俱乐部
Welcome to the fan club of the first real Turkish serial killer.
尽一切努力阻止他们
Do whatever it takes, but stop them.
图凡·埃里博尔，凶手曾把我们从对他的追踪中甩掉
Tufan Elibol, whom the killer used to throw us off his track
将有助于我们抓住他
will be instrumental in catching him.
凶手将成为自己游戏的受害者
The killer will be a victim to his own game.
出去吧
Go on, get out.
我的头是泡沫状的云
Clouds foaming overhead.
我的内外都是大海
The sea within, the sea without.
我是古尔哈内公园的一棵核桃树
I'm a walnut tree in Gülhane Park.
你不知道
Neither you realize this...
警察也不知道
Nor the police.
我今天遇到了一个女孩，她的名字叫做内芙拉·艾尔玛斯
I MET A GIRL TODAY HER NAME IS NEVRA ELMAS
我只相信她，因为内芙拉懂我
I TRUST ONLY HER BECAUSE NEVRA GETS ME
今天是内芙拉的生日，我给她准备了一个礼物
IT IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY TODAY I GOT HER A PRESENT
内芙拉和我有一个秘密
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
我把一切都告诉了内芙拉，但她不相信我
I TOLD NEVRA EVERYTHING BUT SHE WON'T BELIEVE ME
今夜，一颗流星从天而降
TONIGHT, A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
我许了一个愿
I MADE A WISH
我希望他们都死了
I WISHED THAT THEY ALL DIE
-他们都死了 -全死了？
- They're all dead. - All?
乌福克有两个兄弟
Ufuk had two brothers.
其中一个在他的工作地点被枪杀 另一个死在森林里
One of them was shot at his workplace. The other one in the forest.
是我们的案子吗？
Our guy?
-额头上有消息 -他们的父亲在外面
- Messages on both their foreheads. - Their father's outside.
把他们接过来，等着做文书工作
Came to pick them up, waiting on paperwork.
不行 我们需要做验尸
He can't. We need to do an autopsy.
我不能告诉他 我不能告诉他
I couldn't tell him. I could never tell him.
好啦好啦！
Come on! Come on!
我去告诉他
I'll tell him.
儿子！
Son!
是你杀了他们！
You killed them!
-你杀了我的孩子们！-萨利赫
- You killed my children! - Salih...
-萨利赫，别这样 -你杀了我的孩子们！
- Salih, please don't. - You killed my babies!
你杀死了他们！你杀了我的孩子们
You ended them! You ended my babies.
内芙拉 你现在高兴了吗？
Are you happy now? Are you happy now, Nevra?
-得到了想要的东西吗 -闭嘴
- Did you get what you wanted? - Shut up!
如果你一直在寻找杀手，而不是去追捕乌福克
If you had been looking for the killer instead of going after Ufuk.
-他们俩现在一定都还活着 -闭嘴！
- They both would be alive now. - Shut up!
告诉我我在撒谎！
Tell me I'm lying!
该死的！
Damn!
让我死了吧！
I want to die!
我发生什么事了？
What happened to me?
祖哈尔，我们得给你洗胃
We had to pump your stomach, Zuhal.
为什么？
Why?
发生了什么？
What happened?
你酒精中毒了
You had alcohol poisoning when you arrived.
内芙拉？
Nevra?
内芙拉，你在做什么？
Nevra, what are you doing?
没事 我流鼻血了 袖子上沾了血
It's fine. I had a nosebleed. I got blood on my sleeve.
-你还好吗，女儿？-我不好
- Are you alright, daughter? - I'm not.
我一点都不好
I'm not alright at all.
你为乌福感到难过吧？可怜的男孩
You are sad about Ufuk, right? Poor boy.
我无能为力
I'm powerless.
我身边的人在一个个死掉，而我却无能为力！
People are dying around me, and I'm powerless!
我快要发疯了！
It's driving me mad!
我试图控制自己
I try to control myself.
我绷紧体内的所有肌肉，所以没人怀疑
I tense every muscle in my body just so nobody suspects anything.
怀疑什么
Suspect what?
怀疑我害怕，我真的很害怕
That I'm afraid. That I'm afraid. I'm so afraid.
害怕我永远也抓不到杀手！
I'm afraid that I'm never going to catch the killer!
我好害怕！
I'm so afraid!
我好怕
I'm so afraid...
内芙拉，亲爱的
Nevra, my darling...
在人群面前保持不哭，这太难受了。
It was so hard, not crying in front of the crowd.
我跑开了 来到这里
I ran and I ran, and here I am.
我的宝贝 你还像小时候一样
My darling... Just like when you were a child.
快要尿裤子时跑回家里
You'd run home, about to piss your pants.
勉强憋住
You'd barely make it.
你感觉好些了吗？
Are you feeling better?
是的，我觉得好些了
Yes. I think.
-别害怕，内芙拉 -妈妈
- Don't be afraid, Nevra. - Mom...
安静
Hush.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
不要因为害怕而感到害怕
Don't be afraid to be afraid.
害怕又能怎样？
Plus... So what?
我也很害怕
I'm afraid, as well.
不要怕
You're never afraid.
已经过去了
That was then.
我好怕你会发生什么事
I'm so scared that something will to happen to you.
给我洗吧
Come on, I'll wash it.
另外……
And...
他们甚至都不会沾上血迹
They can't even get a bloodstain out...
但他们可以成为警察
Yet they go become cops.
你是个真警察
Some cop you are.
-有人给你送花了，祖哈尔-谁？
- Someone sent you flowers, Zuhal. - Who?
-我 -感觉好一些了就可以出院
- Me. - You can leave when you're feeling better.
-你没走吗？-没
- You didn't go? - No.
你整夜都在这里吗？
You were here through the night?
喂？
Hello?
对，我在这
Yes, I'm here.
文件在我这
I have the file.
你在哪？
Where are you?
喂？
Hello?
喂？信号不好 喂？
Hello? You're breaking up. Hello?
塞米尔，我很抱歉
Cemil, I'm so sorry.
我好尴尬 不知道该说些什么
I'm so embarrassed. I don't know what to say.
我甚至无法想象我把你放在了什么位置
I can't even imagine the spot I put you in.
我应该辞职
I should quit the job.
我该怎么办，塞米尔？
What am I to do, Cemil?
每周浇水两次
WATER IT TWICE A WEEK
Water it twice a week...
跟我一起走吧
And come with me. Let's go.
-你现在要做什么？-回到伊斯坦布尔
- What will you do now? - Get back to Istanbul.
我要问你一件事
I need to ask you something.
你为什么撒谎，塞利姆和你？
Why did you lie, Selim and you?
关于房子如何被烧毁的
About how the house burned down.
我为什么要撒谎？
Why would I lie?
我已经跟你说过
I already told you.
塞利姆忘了吃药 产生了幻想
Selim forgets to take his pills and hallucinates.
-就是这样 -好吧，如果你这样说的话
- That's all. - Fine. If you say so.
如果我知道什么，我为什么不告诉你？
Why wouldn't I tell you if I knew something?
有一些会让你害怕的事情我都已经忘记了
There's something that scares you. I'd forgotten about it.
什么事？
What's that?
你总是害怕一个人呆着
You're scared of being left alone. You always were.
如果塞利姆发生什么事情，你会怎么做？
What would you do if something were to happen to Selim?
如果你知道我害怕一个人呆着，
If you knew that I was scared of being left alone,
那你为什么离开？
why did you up and leave?
你没带我去伊斯坦布尔
You didn't take me to Istanbul.
你怕寂寞，而我怕你
You were being scared of loneliness, and I was scared of you.
好！那就别再流眼泪了
Fine! Then don't come here with tears in your eyes ever again.
为什么不呢？你不是告诉我不要害怕吗？
Why shouldn't I? Didn't you tell me not to be afraid of being afraid?
照顾好自己
Take care.
喂？
Hello?
信号不好，我听不到你说话
You're breaking up. I can't hear you.
喂？
Hello?
门开了
The door is opening.
站住！别动！
Stop! Stop!
报警！加利普！报警！
Call the police! Call the police, Galip!
-你还好吗？-拿枪
- Are you alright? - Take your gun.
你还好吗？
Are you alright?
-发生了什么？他们找到他了吗？-我刚得到消息
- What happened? Did they find him? - I just got word.
他被困在购物中心的车库里
He's trapped in a shopping centre's garage.
是的，我们已将所有出口都被封锁了
Yes. We have all the exits blocked.
这是唯一的出口 他肯定在这里
This is the only exit. He's definitely in here.
我们走吧！
Let's go!
我发现了他的服装 他上屋顶了！
I found his costume. He's going up to the roof!
老实说
To be honest...
我甚至不喜欢酒精的味道，塞米尔
I don't even like the taste of alcohol, Cemil.
但是当我喝了第一杯之后
But after I have that first glass...
有些事情发生了
Something happens...
我无法阻止自己
I can't stop myself.
我只想喝酒
All I want to do is drink.
无论如何都要喝
No matter what.
不管发生什么
Come what may.
“我现在只需要喝一杯，只要再喝一杯”
"All I need right now is a drink. Just let me have one more drink."
我无法阻止自己
I can't stop myself.
有一位作家叫布科夫斯基，你可能听说过他
There this writer called Bukowski, you might've heard of him.
你知道他说什么吗？
You know what he said?
他说喝酒是自杀的一种形式
He said drinking is a form of suicide.
他说喝酒使自己昏迷那是企图自杀
He said drinking yourself unconscious is attempted suicide.
-我不想死，塞米尔 -你确定吗？
- I don't want to die, Cemil. - Are you sure?
当然 我甚至一点都不想谈论这个
Of course I am. I don't even want to talk about this.
和你谈论这个对我来说很尴尬
Talking about this with you is such an embarrassment for me.
伤害别人才令人尴尬，祖哈尔
Hurting someone else is embarrassing, Zuhal.
伤害自己没有什么尴尬的
There's nothing embarrassing about having hurt yourself.
你的问题已经够多了
You have enough problems as it is.
-你要离开吗？-不
- Would you like to leave? - No.
-我们应该留下来 -好
- We should stay. - Alright.
我应该告诉你为什么我们在这里
I should tell you why we're here, then.
坎布拉有一位名叫图兰的长者
There was this elder in Kambura. Turan.
他有一天把我带到一边，告诉我我不是第一个
He took me aside one day and told me I wasn't the first.
我问他是什么意思
I asked him what he meant.
“你不是第一个由坎布兰人支付学费的男孩
"You're not the first boy whose education the Kamburan people paid for.
他说：“他们在你之前还付了三个孩子的学费。”
"They paid for three more children before you." he said.
我很惊讶
I was surprised.
我问他这些人在哪里，他们现在做什么
I asked him where they were, what they did now.
他们付了第一人的学费。他说他是一个好学生。
They paid for the first one's education. He said he was a good student.
大学毕业后开办企业赚了很多钱
Finished college. Started a business. Made a lot of money.
但是他忘记了坎布拉
But he forgot about Kambura.
他再也没有回来过
He never went back to Kambura.
他说有时他们会在电视上看到他，但马上就换频道
He said they sometimes saw him on TV, but changed the channel immediately.
人们为第二个男孩也交了学费
There was a second boy. They paid for his education, as well.
“他读完大学，
"He finished college,
然后人们把他送到伦敦攻读研究生学位”
and we sent him to London for a graduate degree."
但是他却成了赌徒
But he became a gambler.
坎布拉人给他凑得所有钱
All that money that the Kamburans scraped together...
他在赌桌上全输光了
He lost it all on roulette.
显然，他进了监狱
Apparently, he was jailed at some point.
在那之后，没有人看到他
After that, no one saw him
也没人再听到过他的消息
or heard of him ever again.
他们最后的希望……
Their one last hope...
他们付了最后一个男孩的学费
They paid for one last boy's education.
他进了医学院
He got into medical school.
但是他开始喝酒
But he started drinking.
我遇见了他
I met him, actually.
他的名字是拉希姆
Rahim was his name.
比我大五六岁
Five-six years older than I was.
我去找他
I went up to him...
“拉希姆，
"Rahim,
整个村庄都取决于你”
a whole village depends on you."
“你会成为一名医生
"You'll become a doctor
并治愈那些曾养育你的人”
and cure the people who raised you."
你知道他对我说什么吗？
You know what he said to me?
他告诉我，他们从未问过他是否想要接受教育
He told me they never asked him if he wanted an education.
告诉我他们应该自学
Told me they should educate themselves.
我们就在这里进行了交谈
It was right here that I had that conversation
和拉希姆交谈，祖哈尔
with Rahim, Zuhal.
他是这家医院的实习生
He was an intern at this hospital.
他来这儿偷偷的喝酒
He came down here to drink in secret.
现在
Now...
我告诉你为什么我们在这里
I'll tell you why we're here.
你要做出决定
You're going to make a decision.
我再也没有见过拉希姆的脸
I never saw Rahim's face again.
我还能见到你的脸吗？
Will I get to see yours?
我父亲也从未问过我，塞米尔
My father never asked me, either, Cemil.
他从没问过我任何事
He never asked me anything.
从来没有问过我是否要去寄宿学校
Never asked me if I wanted to go to boarding school.
是否想上大学
If I wanted to go to college...
他总是离我很遥远
He was always so distant.
我告诉他我要去澳大利亚
I told him I was moving to Australia.
“永别了，”他说
"Farewell," he said.
我好寂寞
I was so lonely.
有时候我看着老照片
I sometimes look at my photos from those days.
我总是一个人
I'm always by myself.
在照片中
In the photos,
有美丽的风景
there are beautiful landscapes.
美丽的桥梁
Beautiful bridges...
塑像
Statues...
还有我
And me...
只有我
Just me...
你知道我到底想要什么吗？
You know what I'd actually like?
我想要照片……
I want the photos...
我希望照片中有妈妈
I want the photos to have my mom in them.
我想要我妈妈，爸爸和我在一起
I want my mom, my dad and I together.
其他什么都不要
I want nothing else in the photos.
什么都不要了
I want nothing else.
即使我们站在最好的风景前
Even if we're in front of the best view,
在世界上最美丽的地方
in the most beautiful place in the world,
我希望那一切都消失掉，只留下我们
I want all of it gone. I want us and only us to remain.
因为……
Because...
我们有彼此就足够了
We'd be enough for each other.
但事实并非如此
But it didn't turn out that way.
我记得
I'd remember.
即使照片没有其他内容
Even if there were nothing else in the photos,
我看着爸爸妈妈的脸
I'd look at my mom and dad's faces,
我知道
and I'd know that
我们站在一个巨大的瀑布前
we were standing in front of a huge waterfall.
我知道那不在照片里
I know it's not in the photo,
而是我们站在一棵巨大的梧桐树旁
but we're standing by a huge sycamore tree.
这对我来说就足够了
That would be enough for me. But...
但是从来没有那样
But it was never like that. Never.
这些照片只有我一个人
The photos have only me in them.
和落日
And the setting sun.
落日
The setting sun.
太阳
The sun.
太阳总是在那里
There it is, always.
但这是背景
But it's setting.
我……
I...
我从来没能原谅我的父亲 塞米尔
I've never been able to forgive my father, Cemil.
-他一定有原因 -我希望他能和我分享
- He must've had a reason. - I wish he'd shared it with me.
-走吧，塞米尔，我们离开这里吧？ -当然，走吧
- Let's go, Cemil. Let's get out of here? - Sure. Let's go. However...
我需要你向我保证
I need you to make me a promise.
-我保证永远不会再喝酒 - 不，不是
- I promise never to drink again. - No. It's not that.
还有别的
It's something else.
答应我，你永远不会忘记这个地方和这个气味
Promise me you'll never forget this place. And this smell.
我保证 我永远不会忘记
I do. I promise. I'll never forget it.
你父亲曾照顾我 现在轮到我照顾你
Your father looked after me. It's my turn to look after you now.
说什么傻话
That's nonsense.
我的工作是照顾你
My job is to look after you.
-别这样说 -不
- That's nonsense. - No.
那不一样
That's different.
回答我这个问题
Answer me this one question.
照片里有我的位置吗？
Is there room for me in that photo?
塞米尔？
Cemil?
我们结束了
We're done here.
-你还好吗？冷吗？-我很好，也许有点冷
- Are you alright? Are you cold? - I'm fine. A bit cold, maybe.
-别担心，你会克服的 -非常感谢
- Don't worry. You'll get over it. - Thank you so much.
曾经有一位作家
There's this writer.
名叫库伯
Named Coubert...
他说过
He said that...
爱是地球上唯一的冒险
Love is the only adventure left on this earth.
他就是这么说的
That's what he says.
我懂了
I see.
停尸房
MORGUE
开玩笑的吧？
This is a joke, right?
车库只有一个入口和一个出口
There's only one entrance and one exit to the garage.
但是里面没有人
But there's no one inside...
在你的许可之下，
With your permission,
我想带它去实验室进行DNA分析
I'd like to take this to the lab for DNA analysis.
当然可以
Sure, take it.
内芙拉在吗？
Is Nevra around?
是的，她在这里
Yeah. She's here.
我想问你点事儿
I want to ask you something.
你知道对一个谋杀专家来说最危险的是什么吗?
Do you know what's the most dangerous thing for a murder specialist?
痴迷
Obsession.
你有个主意
You get an idea.
然后你就开始相信它了
Then you start believing it. It takes hold in your mind.
然后变成迷恋 它蒙蔽你的双眼
Then it turns into an obsession. It blinds you.
当然，你总是可以有理论的
You can always have theories, of course.
但是你知道理论和阴谋之间的区别吗？
But do you know the difference between a theory and a conspiracy?
我也可以告诉你
I'll tell you that, as well.
理论很明智
Theories are smart.
阴谋论是疾病
Conspiracy theories are sicknesses.
因为一个理论的证据是基于真理的
Because the evidence for a theory is rooted in truth.
但是阴谋的证据是另一种阴谋论
But the evidence for a conspiracy is another conspiracy theory.
换句话说，阴谋本身
Itself, in other words.
即使错了也是对的
It's right even when it's wrong.
阴谋论永远不会错
A conspiracy theory is never wrong.
你知道还有谁永远不会错吗？
You know who else is never wrong?
愚蠢的人
Dumb people.
不要误会我的意思，我不仅是在说你，也在说我自己
Don't get me wrong. I'm not only talking about you, talking about myself, as well.
这就是为什么我们要一起构建逻辑边界
That's why we're going to build a perimeter of logic together.
我们会经常碰面 直到我们找到真相
We'll keep running into each other. Until we find the truth.
我们将会考虑到每一个可能性
We will consider every single possibility.
甚至是与坎布拉无关的可能性
Even the possibility that none of this has anything to do with Kambura.
-是谁？-他身上没有身份证
- Who is it? - He didn't have an ID on him.
我没有和他说话 等着你来，塞米尔
I didn't talk to him. I waited for you to arrive, Cemil.
好，我们来看看他与坎布拉的关系到底是什么
Good. Let's find out what's his problem with Kambura.
顺便说说
By the way...
你应该很高兴乌福克自杀了
You should be glad that Ufuk handled himself.
是的，塞米尔 可悲的是我们无法阻止他
Yes, Cemil. We couldn't stop him, sadly.
你将功补过了
You made up for it, though.
-长官，他与受害人的关系…… -内芙拉
- Sir, his connection to the victim... - Nevra...
-你在说房子吗？-是的
- Are you talking about the house? - Yes.
内芙拉，我们去过那里 你也看过了报告
Nevra, we went there. You read the report.
没人纵火
Nobody burned it.
我不相信那个报告
I don't believe that report.
-是吗 -是的
- Is that so? - Yes.
基于什么理由？你妈妈的丈夫吗？ 他叫什么名字？
On what grounds? Your mom's husband? What was his name?
塞利姆
Selim.
乌福克告诉我们的事呢？他的兄弟被杀了
What about what Ufuk told us? His brothers were killed.
你去那里审问乌福，结果引发了彻底的混乱
You went there to interrogate Ufuk and utter chaos took over.
我接到了政府部门的电话，并询问了坎布拉的情况
I got calls from the ministry asking what's going on in Kambura.
我发誓我对坎布拉一无所知
I swear I don't know anything about Kambura.
我甚至不知道它在哪里！
I don't even know where it is!
我发誓我不是凶手！
I swear I'm not him!
不要！
Please don't!
说话！你为什么杀死这些人？说话！
Speak! Why did you kill all those people? Speak!
但是先生，我们也了解到
But sir, we also know that
死者纳兹·切尔基斯也与坎布拉有联系
the deceased Naz ??rtük is also connected to Kambura.
-她曾在市政厅工作 -当然，但是什么时候？
- She worked in the municipality office. - Sure, but when?
二十年前？四十年前？什么时候？
Twenty years ago? Forty years ago? When?
-请不要！请不要！-告诉我你是谁
- Please don't! Please don't! - Tell me who you are.
你想从那些人那里得到什么？为什么要杀掉那个女人？为什么？
What did you want from those people? Why did you shoot that women? Why?
他们会杀了我的！
They'll kill me! They'll put me in the ground!
我是才是会杀掉你的人！
I'm the one who'll put you in the ground!
我会把你埋得很深，以至没有人能发现你
I'll bury you so deep that no one will see you ever again.
好吧，那这样呢？
Alright! How about this?
我今天接到缉毒局的电话
I got a call from narcotics today.
在停车场被杀的那个女人，你知道她是谁吗？
The woman who was killed in the parking garage, you know who she is?
我知道她在阿塔物流公司当过会计
I know that she worked at a logistics firm as an accountant.
不是，根本没有合格物流公司
Not even close. There's no such logistics firm.
他们在贩毒，内芙拉
It's a front. They were running drugs, Nevra.
缉毒局已经追踪了他们六个月
Narcotics has been after them for six months.
他们说服那个女人转为证人
They convince the woman to turn state's evidence.
他们本该在今天见面
They were supposed to meet today.
她去办公室收集证据
She went to the office to gather evidence.
但是她死了 所以那些证据没有了
But she's gone. So is the evidence.
现在 你还觉得
Now. Do you still think...
谋杀案与坎布拉有关吗？
That the murders are connected to Kambura?
我在报纸上看到了
I saw it in the papers.
一个穿着猫服装的人正在杀人！
A guy in a cat costume was killing people after people!
我说的那些人给了我那女人的情报
The people I told you about gave me the hit on the accountant woman.
我刚出狱
I just got out of prison.
我不能回去坐牢 但是我需要钱！
I couldn't go back in. But I needed the money!
所以我穿了猫服装，我认为那是个好主意
So I donned the cat costume. I thought it would be a good idea.
他杀了四个，五个，这么多人！
He's killed four, five, so many people!
我以为可以算在他头上
I thought I could pin it on him.
我以为我做的事不会有人知道 你会对我做什么？
I thought it would be forgotten. What will you do to me?
来吧！
Please!
动手吧！
你怎么不说话
Why aren't you saying anything? Please!
告诉我你收了多少钱，混蛋 快告诉我！
Tell me how much you were paid, you bastard. Tell me!
如果这还不足以令人信服，这是那个泰拉齐的档案
If all that isn't convincing enough, here's the file on that Terazi guy.
阅读他的档案
Read his file.
上面写的什么
What does it say?
继续大声朗读
Go ahead. Read it out loud.
-创伤后应激障碍 -是的！
- Post-traumatic stress disorder. - That's right!
他病了！
He was sick!
但是我做了什么？
But what did I do?
我问自己：“内芙拉说得对吗？”
I asked myself, "What if Nevra's right?"
如果是他们把那所房子烧毁了怎么办？如果那个报告是假的怎么办？
What if they burned that house down? What if that report was fake?
然后现在发生了什么？
Then what happened today?
我们发现被杀的那个女人与坎布拉毫无联系
We found out that the woman who was killed had nothing to do with Kambura.
我是怎样做的？ 我接受了
What did I do? I accepted that.
现在，内芙拉，我求你了……该你接受事实了
Now, Nevra, I'm begging you... It's your turn to accept it.
如果要在受害者之间寻找联系，找找其他方向吧！
If you want to look for connections between the victims, look elsewhere!
忘了那座被烧毁的房子！
Forget about that burnt down house!
听着，内华拉
Listen, Nevra.
有时候事情并没有像我们期望的那样发生
Sometimes things don't turn out the way we expect them to.
我们希望它是另一种方式。我们以为它是。但并不是
We want them to be another way. We imagine them to be. But they're not.
不过是幻想罢了
They're nothing but illusions.
出去吧
Get out.
然后我们接到一个电话，醒了过来
Then we get a phone call, and wake up.
先生，我可以拿那个文件吗？
Sir? Can I have that file?
我都白说了，不是吗？
I wasted my breath, didn't I?
无论如何你都会做你想做的
You'll do what you want anyway.
当然可以
Sure. Take it.
做你想做的
Do what you want.
我很高兴我们终于见面了
I'm so glad we finally got to meet.
我一直在告诉他
I've been telling him.
如果你没有来找我，我会去找你的
If you hadn't come to me, I'd have come to you.
实际上我正准备去了 我甚至有你的地址！
I was almost about to, in fact. I even have your address!
你要知道
As you might guess,
与患者家人沟通对我们来说是很重要的
communication with patients' families is a must for us.
尤其是像你父亲这样的病人
Especially when it comes to patients like your father.
与他们亲近的人非常重要
It's very important that the people close to them
聚在一起支持他们
get together to support them.
-再次欢迎你，祖哈尔 -谢谢
- Again, welcome, Zuhal. - Thank you.
我准备了一些问题
I have some questions prepared.
来办公桌这边，我来问问题
Let's move to the table and I can begin asking them.
我希望你有在做功课
I hope you've been doing your homework.
阿加，我不知道我为什么同意了这件事
Agah, I don't know why I said yes to this!
这太疯狂了！我必须告诉医生真相
This is madness! I have to tell your doctor the truth.
你会告诉他什么？别傻了
What will you tell him? Don't be silly.
-我可以告诉他，这只是个玩笑 -你不能了，为时已晚
- I can tell him it was all a joke. - You can't do that. It's too late.
那我告诉他真相
I'll tell him the truth, then.
我可以告诉他阿加的女儿正在接受癌症治疗
I'll tell him Agah's daughter is undergoing cancer treatment.
他认为告诉她会让她不高兴
He thinks telling her will upset her.
他担心你可能要去他的家，所以我们想到了这个计划
He was worried that you might want to visit his home, so we came up with this.
贡卡，亲爱的，拜托！
Gonca, my girl, please!
如果你不愿意为我做，那就为尼穆尔做
If you won't do it for me, do it for Münir.
你已经担任它的兽医很多年了，你几乎养育了尼穆尔！
You've been his veterinarian for years. You practically raised Münir!
先不说这个 祖哈尔也很重要啊！
Let's forget about that, even. Zuhal is what's important here!
如果祖哈尔发现父亲病了，祖哈尔会怎样？
What would Zuhal do in her state if she found out her father's sick?
你从医很多年了
You're a doctor of many years.
你能承担这样的责任吗？
Could you take such a responsibility?
你不知道在癌症治疗方面乐观是多么重要吗？
Don't you know how important optimism is when it comes to cancer treatment?
但是接下来，阿加，我们还能维持多久呢？
But what next, Agah? How long can we keep it up?
已经结束了，后面也没什么事了
It's already done. There's nothing to keep up.
他有你的电话 他可能会打给你一次
He has your number. He might call you once, if that.
你只需点头就可以了
You'll just nod your head and be done with it.
真是令人尴尬，不得不撒谎，我很害怕
It was so embarrassing, having to lie. I'm terrible at it.
-你认为他能看出来吗？-当然不能！
- Do you think he could tell? - Of course not!
你真是个好演员！我敢肯定，他绝对不会怀疑你
You were such a great actor! I'm sure he'd never even suspect you.
我现在可以做任何你想做的事
I'll do whatever you want from me now.
我不想再经历这个了
I don't want to go through this again.
我希望祖哈尔能恢复健康
And I hope Zuhal gets her health back.
阿门 谢谢你
Amen. Thank you.
-我可以载你 -真的不用了
- I could give you a ride. - It's fine, really.
好吧，那么非常感谢
Alright. Alright, then. Thank you so much.
你在那里很棒，当之无愧的奥斯卡演员
You were great in there. You deserved an Oscar, I'm telling you.
阿里，我需要一个电话号码
Ali, I need a phone number.
十年前曾在坎布拉医院工作的
Used to work at Kambura Hospital. It's been ten years.
精神科医生内地姆·多埃鲁
Psychiatrist Nedim Do?ru.
好的
Of course.
内芙拉
Nevra...
那套愚蠢的猫服装奏效了 他们发现了一些DNA
The stupid cat costume worked. They found some DNA on it.
他们正试图找到一个匹配的人
They're trying to find a match for it.
如果他们得到匹配，那一切就结束了
If they get a match, this is over.
我要去监督三胞胎的尸检
I need to oversee the autopsy of the triplets.
你可以跟进DNA检测 祝你好运
You can follow up on the DNA. Good luck.
你也是
To you, as well.
谢谢
Thanks.
终于……
Here we are...
我们使这个历史性的时刻永生
We're immortalizing this historic moment.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
-写我的回忆录 -这样啊
- Writing my memoir. - Sure you are.
回忆录中会写什么？你最后死了吗？
What happens in your memoir? Do you die at the end?
从医学角度来说没死，但是我的职业生涯死了
Medically, no. But my career? Yes.
-为什么？-什么为什么？
- Why? - What do you mean, why?
你知道每天有多少具尸体送进来吗？
Do you know how many corpses come in here every day?
我们应该报警吗？
Should we call the police or something?
我工作太多了，我忘了我的地方看起来像什么
I work so much I've forgotten what my place looks like.
我在听，帖木儿
I'm listening, Timur.
同一天出生，同一天死亡
Born on the same day, died on the same day.
真正的三胞胎
Proper triplets.
真是个好调查！
That's some investigating!
喂？内芙拉？
Yes, Nevra?
真的吗 我马上过去
Really? I'll be right there.
-他们找到他了吗？-你怎么知道的？
- Did they find him? - How did you know?
这种情况经常发生，每当我开始说话…
That's how it always is in this place. Whenever I start to speak...
去吧 你这次可能真的能抓到他
Go on. You might really have him this time.
帖木儿，你的嘴是不是拉稀了？
Timur, do you have diarrhea of the mouth or something?
-欢迎，努赫特 -谢谢
- Welcome, Nükhet. - Thank you.
这个给你
This is for you.
-谢谢 -不用谢
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
-你真优雅 -一点都不
- You're so classy. - Not at all.
我希望我没有让你等待太久
I hope I haven't kept you waiting for too long.
我已经等了十年了 我住在这里
I've been waiting for ten years. I live here.
-我们要出去吃饭了吧？ -是的
- We're going out for dinner, right? - Yes.
我们已经到了，就在这里
We're already there. This is it.
-是吗 -是的，你先清
- This is it? - Yes. After you.
多么美丽的建筑
What a beautiful building.
边缘有些粗糙，但仍然很宏伟
It's a bit rough around the edges, but it's still magnificent.
阿卜杜勒哈米德二世建造了它
Abdulhamid the Second built it.
他让一位意大利建筑师为意大利歌剧演员设计了这栋楼
He had an Italian architect design it for use by Italian opera singers.
其实很有趣
Actually, fun fact.
这是伊斯坦布尔的第一座带有电梯的建筑
This is the first building with an elevator in Istanbul.
这就是为什么电梯总是坏掉
That's why it keeps breaking.
真的很棒，所有的房客酒吧都像这样吗？
Truly wonderful. Are all the tenants bars like this one?
不，只有一个，楼上有一个民间酒吧
No. There's just this one, and a folk bar upstairs.
还有一家拥有神韵的小餐馆，就是我们要去的地方
And a trattoria with divine mezzes. That's where we're going.
我就住在这里，但仅此而已
I live here, of course. But that's it.
晚上不吵吗？
Doesn't it get loud at night?
以前很吵
It used to.
他们以前在民谣酒吧打鼓
They used to play the drums at the folk bar. Made quite a ruckus.
所以我去和他们沟通了一下
So I went and had a word with them.
我们达成了协议 他们现在安静得多
We came to terms. They're much quieter now.
一段时间后你就习惯了，它们都在凌晨2点后关闭
You get used to it after a while. They all close after 2 AM.
只有我和孩子们
Only ones left are me and the kids.
没有别人住在这里了
There's no one else in the building.
真的太棒了，生活如此充实一定很有趣
Truly wonderful. Must be so much fun. So full of life.
阿加
Agah...
我们过去吧，怎么样？
How about we go in there for a start?
音乐省厅很大，我都听不到你说话
The music's so loud. We won't even hear each other.
他们在玩摇滚！
They're playing rock 'n roll!
我已经很久没在贝尤鲁喝啤酒了
It's been such a long time since I've had some beer in Beyo?lu.
让我们从那里开始 等下再上楼
Let's start there. We can go upstairs later.
当然可以，你先清
Sure. Alright. After you.
他们匹配到了猫服装的DNA来源
They've found whose the DNA from the cat costume belongs to.
-特警队出发了吗？-是
- Is the SWAT team on the way? - Yes.
敬你
To you.
-敬你 -敬你
- To you. - To you.
生活真美好，不是吗？
Life's a beautiful thing, isn't it?
是的
It is.
-我们快到了 -告诉他们在我们到之前不要行动
- We're almost there. - Tell them to hold until we're there.
告诉特警队在我们到现场前不要行动
Tell the SWAT team not to go in until we're on the scene.
我有个问题
I have a question.
你是怎么想到写一本名为《生活就是交通》的书的？
How did you come up with the idea to write a book named "Life is Traffic"?
-你怎么看？ -我不知道
- How do you think? - I wouldn't know.
我经历过一次交通事故
I was in a traffic accident.
我在那次事故中失去了丈夫
I lost my husband in that accident.
我在医院待了11个月
I was in the hospital for 11 months.
医生告诉我，我也许不能再走路了
The doctors told me I'd never walk again.
但是我在跳探戈时遇见了你
But I met you while doing the tango.
确实
Indeed...
事故发生后，一切都井然有序
Everything fell into place after that accident.
我意识到生活多么简单
I realized how simple life is.
像交通事故一样简单
As simple as a traffic accident.
像交通一样简单
As simple as traffic.
我喜欢……
I love the image of...
道路标志的图像
The image of road signs.
“呆在外面” “不要掉头”这样的东西
"Stay out." "No u-turns." Stuff like that.
我们随身携带这些路标
We carry those road signs around with us.
停车 开车 你可以在这里停车 你不能在这里停车
Stop. Go. You can park here. You can't park here.
交通规则变成了生活规则 阿加
The rules for traffic, Agah, turn out to be the rules for life.
开门！警察！
Open up! Police!
那场意外是怎么发生的？
How did the accident happen?
-我丈夫违反了交通规则 -什么规则？
- My husband broke a rule. - Which one?
他妈的！
Fuck!
塞法，是我，菲鲁兹！
Sefa, it's me, Firuz!
告诉特警队后退 我来开门
Tell the team to pull back. I'm opening the door.
菲鲁兹
Firuz...
如果你想和某人一起自杀
If you want to commit suicide together,
第一条规则是你应该先问对方
the first rule is you should ask the other person
他们是否也想死
whether they want to die, as well.
菲鲁兹，你还好吗？
Firuz, are you alright?
他是故意这样做的吗？
Did he do it on purpose?
最糟糕的是，我嫁给他时就知道他是什么人
The worst part is, I knew what he was when I got married to him.
我以为可以治愈他
I thought I could heal him. But...
-但又有谁能真正治愈别人呢？ -是的
- Whom can you truly heal, right? - Right...
菲鲁兹
Firuz...
塞法
Sefa...
有枪指着我 让特警队后退
I have a gun pointed at me. Tell the team to pull back.
好的
Alright.
放下武器 放下武器
Lower your weapons. Lower your weapons.
-凶手想要什么？-我不知道 我正在问
- What does he want? - I don't know. I'm about to find out.
我要关门了 好吗？
I'm closing then door now. Alright?
等等 塞法！
Hold on, Sefa!
后退 后退
Pull back. Pull back.
往后退！
Back!
但我确信
But I have no doubt
读完你的书后人们就已经康复了
that people have been healed after reading your book.
也许
Perhaps...
但是我没有为别人写这本书
But I didn't write the book for them.
我写这本书是为了治愈自己
I wrote the book to heal myself.
如果他们想自愈，就需要自己写书
If they want to heal themselves, they need to write books of their own.
说话！你他妈的把钱藏在哪里？
Speak! Where the fuck did you hide the money? Speak!
说话还是吃枪子！快说！
Speak or you get one in the head! Speak!
你还写其他书吗？
Did you write any other books?
没有
No...
我还在构思
I'm still in the investigation part.
-关于什么的？-阿加·贝尤鲁
- What is it about? - Agah Beyo?lu.
什么意思？为什么？
What do you mean? Why?
因为直觉告诉我……
Because something tells me...
没有什么是表里如一的
That nothing is as it seems.
是的，长官
Yes, chief. Alright.
好的长官 我们在外面等
Alright, chief. We're waiting outside.
好的长官 当然
Alright, chief. Of course.
我是菲鲁兹！别开枪，我要出来！
It's Firuz! Don't shoot, I'm coming out!
不好意思 我遇到一点小麻烦
Excuse me. There was a small problem.
我的枪里有两发子弹
I had two bullets jammed in my gun.
-放下你的武器 -很高兴你没事
- Lower your fucking weapons. - I'm glad.
我在无线电里听到消息直接就过来，但被他擒住了
I heard you on the radio and came straight over. He fell on me.
但是我有个坏消息 他不是你要找的人
But I have bad news. He isn't the guy you're looking for.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他是受雇的枪手
He was a hired gun.
他知道有一个连环杀手穿着猫服装到处杀人
He knew there was a serial killer running around in a cat costume.
因此他决定成为一只猫，捉住自己的老鼠
He decided to become a cat and catch himself a mouse.
-我要走了-要去哪里？
- I'm leaving, then. - Where to?
-我待会告诉你-好吧
- I'll tell you afterwards. - Alright.
-你吓到我们了 -怎么会吓到你？
- You scared us. - Why would you be scared?
魔鬼会照顾自己
The devil looks after his own.
我来找内迪姆·多姆医生
I'm here to see Dr. Nedim Do?ru.
你有预约吗？
Do you have an appointment?
请稍等
A moment please.
我知道他是上吊自杀的
So he hung himself. I knew that's how it would end.
-你干嘛去了？ -什么？
- Where have you been? - Excuse me?
我等你十年了
I've been waiting for you for ten years.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我一直在等警察来询问我关于乌福克·泰拉齐的事情
I've been waiting for a cop to come asking about Ufuk Terazi.
那么……
Then...
你怎么不去报警
Why didn't you go to the police?
如果你知道这份报告是怎么写出来的，你就不会问我这个问题了
You wouldn't be asking me that if you knew how this report was made.
我那时刚被分配到坎布拉的国立医院
I had just been assigned to Kambura. To the state hospital there.
在我去之前发生了一件可怕的事
Something horrible had happened. It was before my time.
发生了一起火灾，一栋房子被烧毁了
A fire. A house had burned down.
房子里面的人都死了
The family inside had perished.
他父亲把乌福克带到我这里
They brought Ufuk to me. His father did.
乌福克一开始不想说话
Ufuk didn't want to talk at first.
但是当他知道我不是坎布兰人时，他开了口
But when he realized I wasn't a Kamburan, he opened up.
他一遍又一遍地讲同一个故事
He told the same story over and over again.
他说：是我把房子烧了 我一开始不相信他
I burned the house down, he said. I didn't believe him at first.
我以为创伤改变了他对现实的看法
I thought the trauma had altered his perception of reality.
但是他说的那些细节告诉我他并没有出现幻觉
But how detailed it all was told me he wasn't hallucinating.
他也没说谎 所以我找来了警察
He wasn't lying, either. So I called the police.
我告诉他们发生了什么事，就像我现在告诉你的那样
I told them what happened, just as I'm telling you now.
我告诉他们乌福克认罪了
I told them Ufuk confessed.
有一天，当我夜班时，一个男人来找我
One day, when I was on night shift, a man came to see me.
我记得他对我说的每句话
I remember every word he said to me.
“你会忘记这一切”
"You will forget all about this."
“或者你从人间消失，”他说
"Or you disappear," he said.
我问“你是什么意思，消失？”
"What do you mean, disappear?" I asked.
“你将以这个国家的人们消失的方式消失”
"You'll disappear the same way people all around this country do."
那时候我明白了他的意思
I got what he meant then.
他要我写一份报告
He told me I was to write a report.
所以我就照做了
So I did.
他是谁？
Who was he?
我不知道
I don't know.
你从来没有问过他是谁，他是做什么的？
You never asked who he was? What he did?
内芙拉 我这样跟你说吧……
Look, Nevra. I'll explain it to you this way...
骗子以希望为食
Conmen prey on hope.
骗子来找你说：
A conman comes to you:
“给我一块钱，我会给你十块钱”
"Give me a dollar and I'll give you ten back."
如果你天生贪婪，你就会满怀希望给他钱
And if you're greedy by nature, you get hopeful and give him the dollar.
但是这个国家的骗子们不再贩售希望
But the conmen of this country stopped selling hope.
有一个更简单的方法
There's an easier way.
如果人们很怕你……
People are so afraid of you...
在电话上告诉某人你是警察，他们会把所有钱都给你
Tell someone you're a cop on the phone, and they'll give you every dime.
如果一个国家的骗子不是通过希望而是通过恐惧来欺骗你
If the conmen of a country con you through not hope but fear,
你永远不会问他们他们是谁，或者问他们以什么为生
you never ask them who they are or what they do for a living.
那么……
Then...
如果看到他，你能认出他吗？
Could you identify him if you saw him?
其实
Actually...
那天晚上我真的很害怕
I was really scared that night.
我甚至不敢看他的眼睛
I couldn't even look him in the eye.
但你永远不知道
But you can never tell.
你永远不知道别人会突然想起什么
You can never tell what someone might suddenly remember.
-我也不能 -稍等一下
- Not even I can. - Give me a second.
-我不必再害怕了？ -不用
- I don't have to be afraid anymore? - You don't.
-他做了什么？-他生前是法官
- What did he do? - He was a judge.
重刑法官
Heavy penal court.
这些年来
After all these years...
那真是我肩上的重担
That's such a load off my back.
有时遗忘感觉很好 但其他时候，还是会想起来
Forgetting feels good sometimes. But other times, so does remembering.
我永远不会忘记
I'll never forget it.
他来自哪里？去了哪里？
Where did he come from? Where did he go?
-那警察从哪里来的？-警察？什么警察？
- Where did that cop come from? - A cop? What cop?
那个给我做陈述的警察 第二天早上他跟我说了话
The one who took my statement. He spoke to me the next morning.
他来自哪里？
Where did he come from?
-警察吗？-是的
- The cop? - The cop.
应该是从伊斯坦布尔来的 我没记住他的名字
Probably from Istanbul. I didn't get his name.
他很年轻
He was young. He was a young man.
如果有照片，我也许可以认出他
I might be able to identify him if I saw a photo.
什么事？
What is it?
那是什么？
What's that?
这是我欠你的钱 都还清了
It's what I owe you. It's over. We're even.
我做完你的脏活了
I'm done doing your dirty work.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
告诉我结束了
Tell me it's done.
告诉我你会放我走
Tell me you're letting me go.
假如我让你走
Suppose I let you go.
你所做的事会不会不再萦绕在你心头吗?
Will what you've done stop haunting you?
我为了这些钱杀了人
I killed someone over that money!
哦，菲鲁兹
Oh, Firuz...
你以为你可以用钱还债吗
You think you can pay me back in money?
这是沾血的债务
It's a debt in blood.
顺便问一下，你儿子好吗？
How's your son doing, by the way?
我希望他身体健康
In good health, I hope...
基金会可以满足他的所有需求，对吗？
The foundation sees to his every need, right?
你有任何需要都请告诉我
Let me know if you need anything.
现在问题很难解决
It's a hard condition.
不仅难
Not only hard...
还贵
Also expensive.
不要自责
Don't beat yourself up.
你不是一个坏人
You're not a bad person.
你只是在执行我的命令
You're just doing my bidding.
告诉你的良心，把责任归咎于我
Tell your conscience that the blame's all mine.
会好起来的
It'll feel better.
同时，将它们放回口袋里
In the meantime, put these in your pocket.
这显然是你应得的
You obviously deserved them.
我们可以上楼了吗？你不饿吗？
Shall we go upstairs? Aren't you getting hungry?
不，这样很好
No. This is beautiful.
关掉音乐！关掉！
Turn the music off. Turn it off!
-别挡我 -发生了什么事？
- Get out of my way! - What's going on?
-什么？-出去！
- What? - Get out!
出去！出去！
Get out! Get out!
-快走！快走！我们要关门了！出去！-你在做什么？
- Go! Go! We're closing up! Go on! - What are you doing?
走吧 大叔 出去！
Go on, uncle! Out!
-努赫特！-出去！
- Nükhet! - Go on!
-快出去 大叔！快走！-你以为你在做什么！
- Go on, uncle! Go on! - What do you think you're doing!
-回来，臭婊子！-把他们赶出去！快把他们赶出去！
- Get back, bitch! - Throw them out! Throw them out!
快走，你愁啥？
Go on, what are you looking at?
滚蛋！
Get the fuck out of here!
-他们这个月没有交税！-去尼玛的！
- They didn't pay their tax this month! - Fuck you!
你有什么遗愿吗？
Do you have a death wish or something?
我还真有，你能怎样？
That's exactly what I have. What will you do about it?
-快来人帮帮他 -闭嘴
- Somebody help him! - Shut him up!
努赫特，我真的很抱歉
Nükhet, I'm so sorry. I really am.
这种事情从来没有在这里发生过
This kind of thing never happens around here.
不用担心 这不是你的错
Don't worry about it. It's not your fault.
没办法 除此之外 我玩得很开心
It can't be helped. Besides, I had so much fun.
我很生气，我没对那些混蛋说些什么
I'm mad that I didn't say anything to those two-bit crooks.
别傻了，如果他们有枪怎么办？我们怎么知道有没有枪？
Don't be silly. What if they have guns? How do we know they don't?
交通规则不也是这样吗？永远都不要打架
Isn't it that way in traffic also? You should never pick a fight.
你不知道他们是什么人 如果他们的车上有枪怎么办？
You don't know who anyone might be. What if they have a gun in their car?
我们做的是对的，没有参与他们的事情
What we did was right, not getting involved in their affairs.
谢谢你所做的一切 晚安
Thank you so much for everything. Good night.
晚安
Good night...
-这人穿的什么衣服？-他看起来很荒谬
- Some outfit. What's this now? - He looks ridiculous.
你们是黑手党的人吗？
Are you from the mafia?
嘘，他说了些什么
Hush. It's saying something.
-什么？ -我问你们是否来自黑手党
- What? - I asked you if you're from the mafia.
-他是个疯子 -你喝醉了还是怎样？
- He's a loon. - Are you drunk or something?
你在找麻烦吗？
Are you looking for trouble?
等等，让我看看你的脸！
Hold on. Show me your face. Show it!
算了，我们还要去下个地方
Come on, we have another stop to make at S?tk?'s.
该死的小丑
Fucking clown.
我问你们是否来自黑手党
I asked you if you're from the mafia, my boy.
是的，那正是我们的身份，那又如何呢？
Yes. That's exactly what we are. So what?
这就是做黑手党的下场
Here's the mafia for you.
只是一群小混混罢了
Just a bunch of wannabes.
个人
PERSONAL